Hussam Ghunaim

Visiting Instructor of Computer Science

Lima, OH - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Hussam-Ghunaim/7c0f8007c32ba3f1

.

Lecturer having six years of full-time experience spent in lecturing undergraduate computer science courses. Very

strong administrative, presentation and organizational skills gained from 17 years of full-time employment in education

field. Major tasks in addition to lecturing were:

- * Developed a Datamining course for undergraduate senior students. Below are the major course outcomes:
- · Develop data mining solutions by applying various machine learning algorithms
- Analyze the developed data mining solutions performance quality by applying evaluation techniques.
- Gain practical experience through lab exercise and projects.
- * Prepared lectures' handouts, slides, and lab assignments
- * Graded students' assignments, exams and compiled their results and analysis in Excel sheets
- * Fully utilized the blackboard system through posting all related materials and communicating with students
- * Actively leaded class discussions and encouraged debate

WORK EXPERIENCE

Visiting Instructor of Computer Science

Ohio Northern University - Ada, OH - August 2016 to August 2016

Ada. OH. www.onu.edu

- * Teaching undergraduate computer science courses
- * Supervising capstone project for senior students

Graduate Assistant

Physics Laboratory - Bridgeport, CT - September 2013 to May 2016

www.bridgeport.edu

- * Teaching 9 hours per week
- * Preparing experiments' setups and grading students' reports Cooperating with the physics courses' professor to develop laboratory reports and enhance students' performance

Computer Science Lecturer

Al-Yamamah University - Riyadh, SA - September 2007 to July 2012

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. www.yu.edu.sa

- * Providing academic assistance and advising to undergraduate students.
- * Participating in various academic activities: Curriculum development and committees

EDUCATION

Doctorate of Philosophy in Computer Science & Engineering

University of Bridgeport - Bridgeport, CT May 2017

Master of Science in Internet and Multimedia Engineering

London South Bank University - London December 2005

Bachelor of Science in Physics and Mathematics

United Arab Emirates University February 1993

LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/pub/hussam-ghunaim/68/259/b2b

http://www.researchgate.net/profile/Hussam Ghunaim2

https://youtu.be/dUcl3V7Zw9Y

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• Computer Skills I & II

IT-SKILLS

- * Data mining platforms: KNIME, WEKA, and HADOOP (MapReduce)
- * MATLAB (image processing tool box)
- * Java/C/C++/C# (using Eclipse as an IDE for Java)
- * Microsoft Office and MS-Project
- * Operating Systems (Windows and Linux)
- * Web development tools: Web-Expression, Word Press, HTML, and XML Fundamentals